

Mohamed Feddad

Software developer

Github - SourceForge - PyPI - NPM

Libraries - GMail

Open-source enthusiast and in love with Python, JS and GNU/Linux. Long time user experience with large variety of Linux distributions as personal machines as well as deployment platforms with experience in Shell Bash scripting and Ansible. Python is the programming language that i'm most passionate about and my first language of choice for almost anything: Desktop applications, Web development, Web scrapping and System adminstration with proven experience working with outstanding libraries like Flask, Django, PyQT, PySide and BeautifulSoup. Javascript is the language that i'm most experienced in and been developing with the longest, Web development back-end with ExpressJS, front-end with standard JS, JQuery, Redux and ReactJS. As well as a minor experience in Android and IOS application development with facebook's React-Native.

• Education:

- 1. Bachelor of Software Engineering Limkokwing University (2014 2017)
- 2. Masters of Software Engineering Limkokwing University (2018-2019)

Experience:

- 1. Freelance: With the Saudi investment bank to develop front-end UI for a game show (2016/12)
- 2. Internship and Work: With compos-dz Algerian startup to develop a web-based queue management system as a full-stack developer (2017/03-2018/01)
- 3. Freelance: With Nuvonia a Turkish based company to develop a payment portal and API as a full-stack developer (2018/04-2018/12)

Open-Source:

- 1. FQM: Web based queue management system built with Python Flask and Jquery. Software is featured on ZDNet and has thousands of downloads. (ZDNet) (Downloads)
- 2. Safelock: Python based AES files encryption cross-platform Desktop application, reviewed on Softpedia and featured on ZDNet. (Softpedia) (ZDNet)

Experience in keywords:

Python3/2 - SQLAlchemy - Django - Quart - Flask - Flask-SQLAlchemy - Flask-Login - Flask-WTF - Jinja - PySide - PyQt - Click - Gevent - Asyncio - Multiprocessing - Threading - PyCrypto - PyUSB - Python-escpos - PyInstall r - BeautifulSoup - Unittest - Pytest - SQLite3 - SQLCipher - Javascript - jQuery - jQuery-UI - Less - Animate .css - Bootstrap - NodeJS - ExpressJS - Nunjucks - Webpack - ReactJS - Redux - React-Bootstrap - React-Router